<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Physiotheraphy Winnipeg</title>
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg" />
    <updated>2022-06-22T21:36:05-07:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Therapist</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Conditions that Require Winnipeg Physiotherapy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Therapist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/conditions-that-require-winnipeg-physiotherapy.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/conditions-that-require-winnipeg-physiotherapy.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:36:05-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    If you suffer from any of these injuries, physiotherapy Winnipeg will be beneficial to your recovery. You can recover from surgery with physiotherapy.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p><img loading="lazy" src="https://gaiamamawellness.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/AdobeStock_133529214-1080x675.jpeg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" data-cke-saved-src=" https://gaiamamawellness.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/AdobeStock_133529214-1080x675.jpeg"></p>
<h2>Conditions that Require Winnipeg Physiotherapy</h2>
<p>If you suffer from any of these injuries, physiotherapy Winnipeg will be beneficial to your recovery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Carpal tunnel syndrome</li>
<li>Groin or abdominal complex strain</li>
<li>Pain in the hips or groin</li>
<li>Ligament sprains and tears</li>
<li>Overuse injuries</li>
<li>Tears and muscle strains</li>
<li>Shin splints</li>
<li>Shoulder pathologies</li>
<li>Tennis elbow/golfer's elbow</li>
</ul>
<p>You can recover from surgery with physiotherapy.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What is the best time to see a physiotherapist?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Therapist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/what-is-the-best-time-to-see-a-physiotherapist.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/what-is-the-best-time-to-see-a-physiotherapist.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:35:34-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    What is the best time to see a physiotherapist? The primary profession of physiotherapy helps patients to improve and maintain their physical functions and strength. They learn how to pinpoint the root cause of an injury and/or the multiple factors involved in movement dysfunction and&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>What is the best time to see a physiotherapist?</h1>
<p> </p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://s3-media0.fl.yelpcdn.com/bphoto/93RKPQCxtyJ4qXmS_iMvOg/ls.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" data-cke-saved-src=" https://s3-media0.fl.yelpcdn.com/bphoto/93RKPQCxtyJ4qXmS_iMvOg/ls.jpg"></p>
<h2>What Is Physiotherapy?</h2>
<p>The primary profession of physiotherapy helps patients to improve and maintain their physical functions and strength. They learn how to pinpoint the root cause of an injury and/or the multiple factors involved in movement dysfunction and chronic pain.</p>
<h2>What is the best time to see a physiotherapist?</h2>
<p>A physiotherapist can help you if your mobility and ability to function has changed. This could be caused by a recent injury or surgery. But physiotherapists can also help prevent injury. So instead of waiting for discomfort to change into a loss of function, you would benefit from the help of a skilled and certified manipulative physiotherapist.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Physiotheraphy Winnipeg</title>
        <author>
            <name>Therapist</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/physiotheraphy-winnipeg.html"/>
        <id>https://automaniacmrk.github.io/PhysiotheraphyWinnipeg/physiotheraphy-winnipeg.html</id>

        <updated>2022-06-22T21:33:33-07:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Physiotheraphy Winnipeg Shared Health and the College of Physiotherapists of Manitoba has indicated there is no change to the current requirement for masks to be worn while in health care facilities. We are still implementing the following protocols as well: Welcome to Markham Physiotherapy located&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h1>Physiotheraphy Winnipeg</h1>
<p>Shared Health and the College of Physiotherapists of Manitoba has indicated there is no change to the current requirement for masks to be worn while in health care facilities.</p>
<p>We are still implementing the following protocols as well:</p>
<ul>
<li>Each patient is given a linen change by the staff.</li>
<li>Screening each patient and staff member upon entry</li>
<li>You can physically disengage at any time, even if you are not receiving treatment from your therapist.</li>
</ul>
<p>Welcome to Markham Physiotherapy located in Winnipeg Manitoba Canada. South Winnipeg is served by our pain management and injury services. We hold ourselves to the highest standard in order to achieve the best possible outcomes for those that seek our care.</p>
<p>At the heart of our practice is the promise to facilitate well being to the best of our abilities, and to approach everyone with compassion, honesty and integrity. Listening is a vital part of what we do.</p>
<p>Recovery from injury or illness requires a balance of education, rehabilitation and confidence. Markham Physiotherapy works as your partner on the road to better health and mobility by providing you with the most beneficial rehabilitation techniques, and the most up-to-date information about your injury. We will help you to build confidence to empower you in the healing process.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://img1.wsimg.com/isteam/stock/pYYa6qn" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Why Choose Us?</h2>
<ul>
<li>We are well established in the community - our first clinic was founded in 1985.</li>
<li>The clinics have been recently renovated and are extremely clean.</li>
<li>We offer convenient hours, including early morning, evening and Saturday appointments. If you can't make it in person, we offer virtual physiotherapy appointments - for anyone in Manitoba.</li>
<li>We bill directly to Manitoba Public Insurance, the Worker's Compensation Board, Blue Cross and many other insurance providers.</li>
<li>With your consent, we collaborate with your doctor, dentist, chiropractor, registered massage therapist, or personal trainer to facilitate your recovery.</li>
<li>We are a learning and teaching facility - our clinics are approved by the University of Manitoba for physiotherapy students.</li>
</ul>
<h2>What Should You Expect When You Visit A Physiotherapist At Primus Physiotherapy?</h2>
<p>Your injury could make it more difficult for you to perform your daily tasks or work if you have been in an accident.</p>
<p>Your physiotherapist in Winnipeg can treat you, no matter the nature of your injury. No matter if you are recovering from surgery, or have a broken muscle, Winnipeg physiotherapy can help you get back your mobility and flexibility.</p>
<p>Because it's all about you, your session will be special because each one is unique. In general, here's what happens:</p>
<ul>
<li>We learn about your medical history</li>
<li>Your condition will be assessed and diagnosed by us</li>
<li>A treatment plan is created that outlines both the issues found during the assessment as well as the goals for treatment.</li>
<li>Joint mobilization/manipulation and manual therapy techniques, IMS, and/or electrical modalities in combination with a course of exercises will be used as indicated and acceptable to you</li>
<li>Prescribed assistive devices, bracing, exercise equipment, or other orthopedic supplies if needed.</li>
</ul>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5c1976924cde7a2e0b00338e/1552960417145-CEIUDOF33UHEQ7HIHGT6/P2067392.jpg?format=500w" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Henderson Physiotherapy</h2>
<p>Henderson Physiotherapy can be found in the River East / Kildonan area, conveniently located on Henderson Highway halfway between Downtown Winnipeg &amp; the Perimeter Highway. We treat a wide range of injuries and conditions with an attentive, hands-on, and activity based physical therapy approach. We offer 60min assessments and 30min follow-up appointments. Direct billing to most major insurance companies, WCB, MPI, DND, and DVA is available.</p>
<p>Physiotherapy</p>
<h2>What is the best time to see a physiotherapist?</h2>
<p>A physiotherapist can help you if your mobility and ability to function has changed. This could be caused by a recent injury or surgery. But physiotherapists can also help prevent injury. So instead of waiting for discomfort to change into a loss of function, you would benefit from the help of a skilled and certified manipulative physiotherapist.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C4E03AQGn3WmKtcg8_g/profile-displayphoto-shrink_200_200/0/1612734564613?e=2147483647&amp;v=beta&amp;t=VtJS0wbBSNTPDWROsTXoS6X9DXr9YVtAamJeEsFiLA4" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Boniface Community For Over Twenty Five Years</h2>
<p>The professional staff of physiotherapists and massage therapists at our clinic is committed to helping patients improve their quality of living, reduce pain and restore function, as well as promoting a healthier lifestyle. We provide one-on-one care and personalized treatment programs in a friendly and professional atmosphere.</p>
<p>We treat athletes and the elderly. We treat all injuries including those in need of rehabilitation after a motor vehicle accident (MPI), work injury (WCB), or post-surgery.</p>
<h2>What Is Physiotherapy?</h2>
<p>Physiotherapy is a primary health care profession which helps people to restore, maintain and maximize their strength and physical function and improve their overall well-being. They learn how to pinpoint the root cause of an injury and/or the multiple factors involved in movement dysfunction and chronic pain.</p>
<h2><img loading="lazy" src="https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C4D03AQG75Hkr5nfTWg/profile-displayphoto-shrink_200_200/0/1517496998389?e=1658361600&amp;v=beta&amp;t=DCJ7lT_tLVN72-VNysihhNGkN58Z1Z5uApMuMhn-ea0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Physiotheraphy Winnipeg" width="80%" height="auto"></h2>
<h2>Conditions that Require Winnipeg Physiotherapy</h2>
<p>If you suffer from any of these injuries, physiotherapy Winnipeg will be beneficial to your recovery.</p>
<ul>
<li>Carpal tunnel syndrome</li>
<li>Groin or abdominal complex strain</li>
<li>Hip or groin pain</li>
<li>Ligament sprains and tears</li>
<li>Overuse injuries</li>
<li>Tears and muscle strains</li>
<li>Shin splints</li>
<li>Shoulder problems</li>
<li>Tennis/golfer's elbow</li>
</ul>
<p>Physiotherapy can also help you recover after surgery.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
